sparefoot.com 2009-07-03

# Sparefoot Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy covers the use of the Sparefoot website at [www.Sparefoot.com](http://www.sparefoot.com/) ("Sparefoot") and is designed to assist you in understanding how Sparefoot collects and uses the personal information you provide to Sparefoot and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our site and our products and services. Pursuant to Sparefoot's Terms of Use, you must be 18 years and older to use this site. Therefore this policy makes no provision for individuals under 18 years of age.

This Privacy Policy applies when you visit Sparefoot.com or share your personally identifiable information with Sparefoot, as discussed below. By using the website, you accept this Privacy Policy, which may be updated by us at any time. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy for any reason, please do not use this website or share your personally identifiable information with us as discussed below. Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to this website, and not to any other website linked to or from it. We do not control the privacy policies or practices of others. We encourage you to ask questions and read the privacy policies of other websites before you disclose any personal information.

**_What Information Do We Collect?_**   

When you visit Sparefoot, you may provide us with two types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis and Web site use information collected on an aggregate basis as you and others browse our Web site.

**_Personal Information You Choose to Provide_**   

**Registration Information**

When you sign up for a Sparefoot account or other Sparefoot service, we will ask you for personal information such as your name, user name, email address and an account password. For some services, we will ask you for credit card or other payment account information, a billing address and details about the property you are listing or renting which we will store in encrypted form on secure servers. Sparefoot will not sell or disclose your personally identifiable information to third parties without your explicit consent, except as specified in the Privacy Policy. Except as stated herein, only those persons who Sparefoot reasonably believes need access will have access to your personal information. This includes, but is not limited to, the disclosure of the renter's email address to the lister upon a successful application for storage space. Your personal information may be combined with information Sparefoot collects or acquires from other companies and used to improve and personalize services, content and advertising. Sparefoot may store your personal information for as long as your account has not been deactivated by you. You may deactivate your account by emailing [support@Sparefoot.com](mailto:support@Sparefoot.com).

As part of the listing and renting process, you may obtain personal information about another Sparefoot user such as that user's email address, physical address, telephone number and/or other information. This information should only be used for Sparefoot-related communications and transactions and for no other purpose. You are not authorized or licensed to use this information for any other purpose including, without limitation, the sending of unsolicited commercial messages. You are not authorized to add any Sparefoot user to any email or physical mail list.

**Personal Information You Post in Public Areas**

When you post a message in a Sparefoot forum, chatroom, review or customer feedback, or if you post personal information on your Sparefoot Profile, your Sparefoot Username is visible to other users as is any personal information you may post. If you post personal information anywhere on the website that is accessible to the public or other Sparefoot users, you are advised that such personally identifiable information can be read, collected, used or disseminated by others and could be used to send you unsolicited information or otherwise. Accordingly, you assume full responsibility for posting such information and agree that Sparefoot is not responsible in any way for personally identifiable information you choose to post in these public areas.   

**Service-Related Communications**

When you sign up for a Sparefoot account or service, we will send you a welcome email confirming your sign up. Sparefoot may also send you other service-related messages when, in our sole discretion, it is necessary or advisable to do so. You may not opt out of these service-related communications. If you do not want to receive these messages, you may deactivate your account by emailing [support@Sparefoot.com](mailto:support@Sparefoot.com) from the email address you originally used to sign up. If you do deactivate your account, please be advised that your personal information may remain in Sparefoot's records for some period of time.   

**Administrative Communications**

From time to time, Sparefoot may send you administrative messages by email.    

**Email Information**

If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses.    

**Web Site Use Information**

Similar to other commercial websites, Sparefoot utilizes a standard technology called "cookies" (see explanation below, "What Are Cookies?") and webserver logs to collect information about how Sparefoot is used. Information gathered through cookies and webserver logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, IP address, type of computer used to access the website, language, type of web browers, time spent at our website, and the websites visited just before and just after visiting Sparefoot. We, our advertisers and ad serving companies may also use small technology or pieces of code to determine which advertisements and promotions users have seen and how users responded to them.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).   

Sparefoot uses the Google AdSense network, a service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"), to display ads on our website. Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Users may opt out of the use of this cookie, called the "DART cookie", by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy [here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).    

Sparefoot uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, which uses cookies and tracking code to help analyze how visitors use the website. The information collected (including what browser and operating system is being used, the user's IP address, the pages on Sparefoot's website that the user has visited, the number of page views, and the time spent on the website) is transmitted to and stored by Google. Google uses this information for the purpose of evaluating visitors' use of the website in an aggregate manner, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and Internet usage. Google may transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or to third parties that process information on Google's behalf. Google's Privacy Policy can be read at [here](http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy.html).

**_How Do We Use the Information That You Provide to Us?_**

Broadly speaking, we use personal information for purposes of administering and expanding our business activities, providing customer service and making available other products and services to our customers and prospective customers. Sparefoot may use the personally identifiable information you provide to contact users and deliver information and/or marketing and promotional materials, including through postal mail, e-mail, and other means, as well as to improve its marketing and promotional efforts, and to analyze website usage, improve its content and product offerings, and customize its website content, layout, and services.

**_What Are Cookies?_**   

A cookie is a very small text document, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier. When you visit a website, that site's computer asks your computer for permission to store this file in a part of your hard drive specifically designated for cookies. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites. Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies that originate from their sites. We have no access or control over those cookies. 

**_How Do We Use Information We Collect from Cookies?_**   

As you use our website, the site uses its cookies to differentiate you from other users. In some cases, we also use cookies to prevent you from seeing unnecessary advertisements or requiring you to log in more than is necessary for security. Cookies, in conjunction with our web server's log files, allow us to calculate the aggregate number of people visiting our website and which parts of the site are most popular. This helps us gather feedback in order to constantly improve our website and better serve our customers. Cookies do not allow us to gather any personal information about you and we do not generally store any personal information that you provided to us in your cookies.

**_Sharing Information with Third Parties_**   

We may enter into alliances, partnerships or other business arrangements with third parties who, WITH YOUR EXPLICIT CONSENT, may be given access to personal information including your name, address, telephone number and email for the purpose of providing you information regarding products and services that we think will be of interest to you. 

We also use third parties to facilitate our business, including, but not limited to, sending email and processing credit card payments. In connection with these offerings and business operations, our partners and other third parties may have access to your personal information for use in connection with business activities. As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings. Customer, email, and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions. We may also transfer such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or any dissolution.

**_Notice of New Services and Changes_**   

Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our Web site, new services and special offers we think you will find valuable. As our customer, you will be given the opportunity to notify us of your desire not to receive these offers by sending us an email request at [support@Sparefoot.com](mailto:support@Sparefoot.com).

**_How Do We Secure Information Transmissions?_**   

Email is not recognized as a secure medium of communication. For this reason, we request that you do not send private information to us by email. Some of the information you enter on our website may be transmitted securely via Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), 128 bit encryption services. Pages utilizing this technology will have URLs that start with HTTPS instead of HTTP. Please contact [support@Sparefoot.com](mailto:support@Sparefoot.com) if you have any questions or concerns.

However, as you probably know, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, and other users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collect from the site. Therefore, although we work very hard to protect your privacy, we do not promise or guarantee, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private.

**_How Can You Access and Update Your Information?_**   

You may request access to all your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain in our database by emailing [support@Sparefoot.com](mailto:support@Sparefoot.com).

**_Certain Disclosures_**   

We may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the law or comply with legal process served on us or affiliated parties; (b) protect and defend our rights and property, our site, the users of our site, and/or our affiliated parties; (c) act under circumstances to protect the safety of users of our site, us, or third parties.

**_What About Other Web Sites Linked to Our Web Site?_**   

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our website nor the information or content contained therein. Often links to other websites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that may be useful to the users of our website. 

Please remember that when you use a link to go from our website to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link on our website, is subject to that website's own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

**_Phishing, Spoofing and Spamming_**  

Phishing attacks attempt to steal consumers' personal identity data and financial account credentials. 'Phishers' use 'spoofed' e-mails to lead consumers to counterfeit websites designed to trick recipients into divulging Personal Information such as credit card numbers, account usernames, passwords, and social security numbers. **WE DO NOT SEND E-MAILS ASKING YOU TO PROVIDE OR CONFIRM SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION OR YOUR USERNAME OR PASSWORD!** If you receive such e-mail communication, please forward it immediately to the Site's Privacy Administrator at [support@Sparefoot.com](mailto:support@Sparefoot.com) and then immediately delete the fraudulent e-mail from your computer. We do not engage in the indiscriminate sending of unsolicited bulk messages ("spamming").

**_Privacy and Safety of Children_**  

Sparefoot is concerned about the safety and privacy of children who use the Internet. Sparefoot.com is not designed for or directed to children under the age of 13 and requires by its Terms of Use that users are 18 years of age or older. If you are under the age of 13, please discontinue use of the site. Consistent with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 ("COPPA"), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under 13 without prior verifiable parental consent. If we become aware that a child under 13 has somehow provided us with personally identifiable information without verifiable parental consent, we will use our best efforts to remove such information from our files. If you believe that your child has provided us with such information without your consent, please e-mail us at [privacy@Sparefoot.com](mailto:privacy@Sparefoot.com) or write to us at Sparefoot, Inc., Attn: Privacy Dept., 445 Landfair Ave, Suite 202, Los Angeles, CA 90024.

**_Disclaimer Regarding International Use_**  

Sparefoot makes no claim that Sparefoot.com is appropriate or lawful for use or access outside the United States. Furthermore, our databases are located in the United States. If you access this website from outside the United States, you do so at your own risk. You are solely responsible for complying with all local laws, rules and regulations regarding online conduct and website access. By sending us your data, you consent to its transfer to and storage within the United States.

**_Disclaimer Regarding Legal Documents_**   

Neither Sparefoot nor any of its employees are attorneys; Sparefoot is not a law firm. Sparefoot can only provide self help services at your specific direction. Sparefoot cannot represent you in court, advise you about your legal rights or the law, or select legal forms for you. Although Sparefoot strives to keep its legal documents accurate, current and up-to-date, due to rapid changes in the law Sparefoot cannot guarantee that all the information on the site is completely current. The law is different from jurisdiction to jurisdiction, and is also subject to interpretation by different courts. The law is a personal matter, and no general legal document like the kind Sparefoot provides can fit every circumstance. Furthermore, the legal information contained on this site is not legal advice and is not guaranteed to be correct, complete or up-to-date. Therefore, if you need legal advice for your specific problem, or if your specific problem is too complex to be addressed by our tools, you should consult a licensed attorney in your area.

This site is not intended to create any attorney-client relationship, and by using Sparefoot, no attorney-client relationship will be created with Sparefoot. Instead, you are representing yourself in any legal matter you undertake through Sparefoot's legal document service. Sparefoot is not a law firm, and the employees of Sparefoot are not acting as your attorney. Sparefoot's legal document service is not a substitute for the advice of an attorney. Sparefoot, Inc. is a registered and bonded Legal Document Assistant, Registration #: LDA-367, Los Angeles County (exp. 08/25/2010). Sparefoot cannot provide legal advice and can only provide self-help services at your specific direction. Sparefoot does not perform the legal services that an attorney performs.

**_How to Contact Us_**  

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, you can e-mail us at [privacy@Sparefoot.com](mailto:privacy@Sparefoot.com) or write to us at Sparefoot, Inc., Attn: Privacy Dept., 445 Landfair Ave, Suite 202, Los Angeles, CA 90024.

**_Your California Privacy Rights_**  

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our customers who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please e-mail us at [privacy@Sparefoot.com](mailto:privacy@Sparefoot.com) or write to us at Sparefoot, Inc., Attn: Privacy Dept., 445 Landfair Ave, Suite 202, Los Angeles, CA 90024.

**_Governing Law and Forum_**

This Privacy Policy is governed by California law. If we have a dispute regarding this policy or your use of our website, you agree that it shall be resolved solely in the state or federal courts located in the County of Los Angeles, State of California.

**_Your Consent_**   

This Privacy Policy describes the ways we collect, store, use and protect your personal information. You accepted this policy when you signed up for Sparefoot's service. Sparefoot may amend its Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amended terms on its site. Amendments to the Privacy Policy will take effect immediately upon posting on the site. You are responsible for checking this Privacy Policy each time you access this website and its services.

**Last modified: December 16, 2008**
